<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SOC 4930 &amp; SOC 5050</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on SOC 4930 &amp; SOC 5050</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Released under the MIT license</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantiative Analysis - Applied Inferential Statistics</title>
      <link>/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/</guid>
      <description>Currently Offered
SOC 4930 &amp;amp; 5050 is Saint Louis University Sociology&amp;rsquo;s undergraduate and graduate introductory statistics course, which is currently being offered for Fall, 2017. This site is for sections taught by Assistant Professor Christopher Prener.
 Course Description This course provides an introduction to applied statistical analysis for both undergraduate and graduate students with an emphasis placed on statistical techniques that are most common in the sociological literature. The statistical techniques introduced include measures of central tendency and dispersion as well as measures of bivariate association.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Before you begin the semester, there are a number of things that I recommend that you do to help set yourself up for success. Before you do anything else, you should read through the Syllabus and the Reading List. Make sure you have a good sense of what is required for the course. If you have questions, bring them to the first day of class!
Account Signups Get Started with Slack We&amp;rsquo;ll be using the messaging platform Slack as a space for &amp;ldquo;virtual office hours&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 01 - Course Introduction</title>
      <link>/week-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/week-01/</guid>
      <description>Lecture Slides  Introducing R and RStudio   At the very end of our first class, I introduced some basic aspects of R and RStudio. Since it was rushed, I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a quick video that summarizes what we went over and introduces some new functions as well. Please watch this before tackling the week two materials.
I have also posted a quick reference sheet for relevant R functions for the week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 20:10:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>Copyright &amp;copy; 2016 Digitalcraftsman digitalcraftsman@protonmail.com
Copyright &amp;copy; 2016 Martin Donath martin.donath@squidfunk.com
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>