<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SOC 4930 &amp; SOC 5050</title>
    <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on SOC 4930 &amp; SOC 5050</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://slu-soc5050.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Analysis - Applied Inferential Statistics</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/</guid>
      <description>Not Currently Offered
SOC 4930 &amp;amp; 5050 is Saint Louis University Sociology&amp;rsquo;s undergraduate and graduate introductory statistics course, which is planned to next be offered for Fall, 2018. Minor revisions to the curriculum are planned for the next edition of the course. Documents should not be considered current if their date is for 2017. This site is for sections taught by Assistant Professor Christopher Prener.
 Course Description This course provides an introduction to applied statistical analysis for both undergraduate and graduate students with an emphasis placed on statistical techniques that are most common in the sociological literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Resources</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/course-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/course-resources/</guid>
      <description>In addition to the Syllabus and the Reading List, there are a number of other course resources you should be aware of.
Course Website This course website will be updated regularly throughout the semester. I&amp;rsquo;ll add a page on the menu for each week, and include links to lecture slides, YouTube videos, and notes about specific topics.
User&amp;rsquo;s Guide The User&amp;rsquo;s Guide is a companion document for the course that covers applications and processes not covered by one of the course textbooks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Before you begin the semester, there are a number of things that I recommend that you do to help set yourself up for success. Before you do anything else, you should read through the Syllabus and the Reading List. Make sure you have a good sense of what is required for the course. If you have questions, bring them to the first day of class!
Account Signups Get Started with Slack We&amp;rsquo;ll be using the messaging platform Slack as a space for &amp;ldquo;virtual office hours&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 01 - Course Introduction</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-01/</guid>
      <description>Handouts Exercise - Values  Exercise - Email  Functions 
Lecture Slides  Introducing R and RStudio   At the very end of our first class, I introduced some basic aspects of R and RStudio. Since it was rushed, I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a quick video that summarizes what we went over and introduces some new functions as well. Please watch this before tackling the week two materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 02 - Working with Data (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-02/</guid>
      <description>General Handouts Lab  Problem Set 01 
Lecture 02a - Introducing ggplot2 Lecture Handouts Functions 
Slides  Video Lecture   Lecture 02b - Grammar of Graphics Lecture Handouts Functions 
Slides  Video Lecture   Lecture 03 - Verbs for Cleaning Data Lecture Handouts Functions 
Slides  Video Lecture   Lecture 04 - Structuring Notebooks Lecture Handouts Functions  Notebook Sample 
Slides  Video Lecture   Data for Assignments The data that you need for many of the assignments this semester is available as an R package named testDriveR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 03 - Describing Distributions</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-03/</guid>
      <description>Handouts Equations  Functions  Lab  Problem Set 02 
Lecture Slides  Using GitHub to Store Working Files for the Course If you want to GitHub to store your working files (as opposed to the finish submission versions you submit via your Assignments repository), you can sign-up for a discounted student plan here. Choose &amp;ldquo;Student&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Individual Account&amp;rdquo;, and answer any additional prompts they have. Be prepared to attach a photo of your student ID.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 04 - Probability and Bayes&#39; Theorem</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-04/</guid>
      <description>Handouts Equations  Lab  Problem Set 02  Weekly Prep 
Lecture Slides  Weekly Prep Instructions I&amp;rsquo;ve posted the first weekly prep of the semester. The instructions are available in the Week-04 GitHub repository. Make sure you submit your work and answers by the beginning of class on Monday!
Replication   Probability in the News FiveThirtyEight just published a great article on the use probability in news media coverage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 05 - The Distribution of Random Variables</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-05/</guid>
      <description>Handouts Equations  Functions  Lab  Problem Set 04  Weekly Prep 
Lecture Slides  Weekly Prep Instructions The instructions for this week&amp;rsquo;s weekly prep are available in the Week-05 GitHub repository. Make sure you submit your work and answers by the beginning of class on Monday!
Replication   Grappling with p-values Here are a couple of links for digging further into what p-values are and how we explain them:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 06 - Foundations for Inference</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-06/</guid>
      <description> Handouts Equations  Functions  Lab  Problem Set 04  Weekly Prep 
Lecture Slides  Weekly Prep Instructions The instructions for this week&amp;rsquo;s weekly prep are available in the Week-06 GitHub repository. Make sure you submit your work and answers by the beginning of class on Monday!
Replication   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 07 - Difference of Means (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-07/</guid>
      <description>Handouts Equations  Exercise  Functions  Lab  Weekly Prep 
Lecture Slides  Weekly Prep Instructions The instructions for this week&amp;rsquo;s weekly prep are available in the Week-07 GitHub repository. Make sure you submit your work and answers by the beginning of class on Monday!
Replication   YAML Headers for RMarkdown Documents The area at the top of your RMarkdown documents is known as a YAML header (Wikipedia site and YAML project homepage).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 08 - Difference of Means (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-08/</guid>
      <description>Handouts Exercise  Functions  Lab  LaTeX  Problem Set 06  Weekly Prep 
Lecture Slides  Weekly Prep Instructions The instructions for this week&amp;rsquo;s weekly prep are available in the Week-08 GitHub repository. Make sure you submit your work and answers by the beginning of class on Monday!
Replication   New and Updated Packages for Class We are going to be using a bunch of new packages this week!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 10 - Correlation (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-10/</guid>
      <description>Handouts Equations  Functions  Lab  LaTeX  Sample Handout  Weekly Prep 
Lecture Slides  Weekly Prep Instructions The instructions for this week&amp;rsquo;s weekly prep are available in the Week-10 GitHub repository. Make sure you submit your work and answers by the beginning of class on Monday!
Replication   Correlation with Binary Variables There is one point missing from today&amp;rsquo;s lecture that comes up on the lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 11 - Correlation (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-11/</guid>
      <description>Handouts Functions  Lab  LaTeX  PS-08  Weekly Prep 
Lecture Slides  Creating Correlation Tables As we discuss this week, R&amp;rsquo;s correlation output leaves much to be desired relative to statistical software applications like Stata or SAS. I&amp;rsquo;ve written a function (based on a few others that are floating around) that adds a bit of flexibility and precision to the correlation calculation process, and returns output with correlation coefficients and statistical significance values combined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 12 - Bivarite Regression</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-12/</guid>
      <description>Handouts Functions  Lab  LaTeX  PS-09 
Lecture Slides  Some Example Code for Class  More on Plots Line Breaks in Plot Text We discussed this informally in class, and I wanted to clarify the technique for adding line breaks here. In situations where the size of the text has been increased or the quantity of text is quite large (a lengthy caption, for example), it is easy for the text to run off the sides of the plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 13 - Multiple Regression (1)</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-13/</guid>
      <description> Handouts Functions  Lab  LaTeX  Workflow  Weekly Prep 
Lecture Slides  Some Example LaTeX Syntax for Class Bibliography File  LaTeX Source  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 14 - Multiple Regression (2)</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-14/</guid>
      <description>Handouts Functions  Lab  LaTeX  PS-10  Weekly Prep 
Lecture Slides  Example Image for Class You can find our example image for download here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 15 - ANOVA</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-15/</guid>
      <description>Handouts Functions  Lab  Workflow 
Lecture Slides  Summary Functions RStudio has an excellent data wrangling cheat sheet that includes a list of the summary functions you can use with dplyr::summarize(). You can access the cheat sheet from their website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 16 - Chi-Squared</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/week-16/</guid>
      <description> Handouts Functions  Lab  Weekly Prep  Workflow 
Lecture Slides  Bar Plots We covered bar plots very quickly during Week-02 of the semester. They are created using the geom_bar() geom in a ggplot2 call:
ggplot(data = mpg, mapping = aes(class)) + geom_bar()  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 20:10:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slu-soc5050.github.io/license/</guid>
      <description>Copyright &amp;copy; 2016-2017 Christopher G. Prener
This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
This is a human-readable summary of (and not a substitute for) the license.
You are free to: - Share — copy and redistribute the material in any medium or format - Adapt — remix, transform, and build upon the material for any purpose, even commercially. The licensor cannot revoke these freedoms as long as you follow the license terms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>